ROSS BRANTLEY

PROFILE

United States Air Force Veteran with background in sales, electronics, communications, literary research and analysis, composition, budget and personnel management in high tempo environments.

Patient leader with emphasis on team safety, attention to detail, training, accountability, and solutions.

CONTACT

PHONE: (808) 219-5510

E-MAIL:

m.ross.brantley@gmail.com

PROFFESSIONAL TRAINING

USAF IT Fundamentals Course USAF Airfield Systems Apprentice Course USAF Project Management Course USAF Fiber Optic Maintenance Course Six Sigma Green Belt Training

PROGRAM PROFICIENT

Microsoft Outlook
Microsoft Excel
Microsoft Word
Microsoft Access
Microsoft Power Point
Microsoft Share Point
Google Docs
Google Sheets
Google Calendar
Google Drive
Adobe Acrobat

AWARDS

Top Graduate: IT Fundamentals Course, Keesler Air Force Base 2015 Airfield System Maintenance Team

of the Year: Pacific Air Forces

2015 Airman of the Year: 15th Operations Group, Joint Base Pearl Harbor-Hickam

SECURITY CLEARANCE

Secret

EDUCATION

FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY

August 2005 – August 2009 Bachelor of Arts in English Language & Literature

COMMUNITY COLLEGE OF THE AIR FORCE

April 2015 – April 2016 Associates in Electronics Systems Technology

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ultimate Washer Inc: Sales

February 2011 - October 2011

- Customer service representative and sales lead for home-use, professional, and industrial cleaning equipment
- Managed sales over \$600k, top salesman for 3 consecutive months
- Coordinated between engineers, suppliers, and shippers to find unique solutions for diverse customer base, domestic and international
- Engaged customers through various leads: face-to-face, phone, email, website engagement, forum posts, and individual follow-ups
- Analyzed supplier costs, inventories, and lead times to advise on price setting, continuation of products on website, ending or renegotiating relationships with specific suppliers
- Sought out new suppliers and new products for website, negotiated credit terms, drop-shipping options, and bulk inventory discount levels with new suppliers
- Professionally guided customers through technical issues, website navigation, parts diagrams, owners' manuals, returns, exchanges, shipping options, and purchases

United States Air Force: Radar Airfield and Weather Systems

January 2012 – January 2020

- Electronics technician for equipment valued over \$5 mil
- Coordinated with multiple agencies to maintain and repair vital navigation aids for safety of flight in high-risk environments
- Promoted to Non-Commissioned Officer in Charge of work center: led
 5-man team servicing 8 organizations across 4 aeographic locations
- Directly supervised 6 employees: responsible for their career progression, safety, technical training, and performance reports

SKILLS

Effective Communicator

- Background in English studies with emphasis on research, citation of sources, proper spelling, and grammar in written communications
- Leader and trainer for over 400 individuals for first aid response, electronics maintenance, and operational security in high-risk areas
- Over 30 public speaking engagements to audiences as large as 250

Work-center Management

- Managed daily operations for 45 military members, 25 local nationals, and 12 vehicles while deployed in a combat zone
- Oversaw budget and spending for 3 work-centers for 3 years

Solution Focused

- Troubleshot and repaired complex communication, navigation, and weather observation systems directly affecting operating aircraft
- Analyzed and sought out root-cause issues for inefficient organizational practices, implemented 5 base-wide solutions affecting 1500 personnel